Dinesh Kumar Rajasekaran

Full Stack Developer



dineshkumarr0597@gmail.com



7904902105





Aiden-Pearce-bytes

SUMMARY

I'm a Mid-level Full-Stack Developer, specialize in Front-end Development and User Interface design. I possess experience in handling projects based on React, React Native, Next13, and Tailwind CSS. My expertise lies in identifying opportunities to improve the frontend design and enhance the overall user experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer in Freelancing Projects

May 2022 - Present // Bangalore, India

- Skilled in Mobile Applications and Web Applications for different clients developed using React and React Native.
- Experience in working with Git, Node and NPM Packages.
- Familiar in integrating and managing REST and SOAP API services.
- Proficient with Atomic UI Design Methodology, also familiar with Clean Architecture.
- Experience in building functional components in both mobile and web platforms.

Technical Engineer @ Gigmo Solutions Private Limited

Nov 2020 - May 2022 // Bangalore, India

- Developed strong problem-solving skills by troubleshooting various complex application related incidents (Microsoft Office 365 products) by coordinating with respective clients.
- Proficient in handling Microsoft Admin Portals such as Exchange, Azure, Teams, SharePoint, Outlook etc.
- > Experienced in handling on-premises local Azure active directory.
- Provided various services such as Domain Management, Office License Management etc. to multiple clients.
- Administered the applications in rotating shifts (24x7) and with occasional 12-hour shifts to provide uninterrupted service to

Backend Developer Trainee @ Xmedia Software Solutions

Jan 2020 – Oct 2020 // Chennai, India

EDUCATION

MS in Software Engineering (5 Year Integrated Program)

Jul 2014 - Nov 2019 @ Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore // CGPA: 7.29/10

Tamil Nadu Higher Secondary Certificate Examination

Jun 2013 – May 2014 @ Lakshmi Garden Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Vellore // Percentage: 72%

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, PHP

Libraries & Frameworks

React, React Native, Next13, Tailwind CSS, Redux

Tools & Platforms

Git, Word Press

Design

Photoshop, Figma, Illustrator.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Board Member @TLA, VIT (2018 - 2019).

Event Organizer @Riviera, VIT (2018 & 2019). Event Organizer @graVITas, VIT (2018 & 2019).

PROJECTS

Netflix Clone

Webapp developed Next.js and Tailwind. Users can able to view, play videos same like Netflix. Used Google and Github Auth for Authentication.

GeoTravel

Responsive Webapp where users will able to explore places and check prices to visit those places. include testimonials section. Contact form etc.

INTERESTS

Music - Travelling